ready okay hi I'm Kevin Sutter I
准备好了，嗨，我是凯文·萨特
recognize a lot of you because this is
认识很多人，因为这是
my fourth session this week so I think
我本周的第四届会议，所以我认为
you've been at a few of the sessions
你去过几次会议
anyway and this is Marcus card and what
无论如何，这是马库斯卡，还有什么
we're going to do today is talk more
我们今天要做的是多谈
from a community perspective I'm going
从社区的角度来看，我要
to start off just by giving some
开始只是给一些
overview of the jacquard Eee community
提花Eee社区概述
at a higher level and then what I want
在更高的水平，然后我想要什么
to do is hand it off to Marcus and let
要做的就是把它交给马库斯，让
him explain well what is this like at
他很好地解释了这是什么样的
the team level because he's the one
团队水平，因为他是那个
that's really been working the nuts and
这真的是在努力工作，
bolts at the lower level
较低级别的螺栓
okay so like I said I'm going to start
好吧，就像我说我要开始
at the higher level with the community a
在更高层次上与社区
couple of these charts you've seen
您已经看过的几个图表
before if you've been following my other
如果您一直在关注我的另一个
presentations this week but the big
本周的演讲，但规模很大
thing here with any community we need
我们需要的任何社区都在这里
participation and it's across all levels
参与，涉及所有层面
so yes I'm involved in you know like the
所以是的，我参与其中，就像
PMC and some of the steering committees
PMC和一些指导委员会
and stuff for Jakarta EE but we also
和Jakarta EE的东西，但我们也
need all the assistance and help at the
需要所有的帮助和帮助
lower levels as well across all the
较低的水平
teams associated with Jakarta EE I put
我把与Jakarta EE相关的团队
this one up because this really shows
这一个，因为这确实显示
the difference of community between what
社区之间有什么区别
used to be with Java EE and how it is
曾经与Java EE结合使用
with Jakarta so Java EE I was looking I
与Jakarta合作，因此我正在使用Java EE
was trying to find a chart that would
试图找到一个图表，
show all of the participants in Java EE
显示Java EE中的所有参与者
because there's a lot of companies a lot
因为有很多公司
of individuals that help I couldn't find
找不到我的帮助对象
anything that this page says Java EE
此页面上说Java EE的所有内容
community and what company do you see
社区以及您看到的是哪家公司
it's only Oracle so it's a very Oracle
这是唯一的甲骨文，所以它是一个非常甲骨文
centered process and deliverable compare
集中的过程和可交付的比较
that with Jakarta EE this is our front
通过雅加达EE，这就是我们的战线
page go to Jakarta EE and this is what
页面转到Jakarta EE，这就是
you see now Oracle still up there they
你现在看到甲骨文仍然在那里
are definitely participating there
肯定在那里参加
they're contributing most everything in
他们贡献了大部分
in here but there's just one vote that
在这里，但只有一票
is equal with everybody else's and that
与其他人平等
is very key that it's a community of all
这是所有人的社区非常关键
of these different vendors projects and
这些不同的供应商项目和
individuals that are trying to develop
试图发展的人
and promote this community so at the
并促进这个社区的发展
very top level Eclipse has defined this
Eclipse的顶级定义
process this entity called a working
处理这个称为工作的实体
group and we have defined a decart EEE
组，我们已经定义了十进制EEE
working group that's a top-level group
最高层的工作组
of it's a consortium of vendors and
这是一个由供应商组成的财团，
projects some individuals that are
投射一些个人
trying to define the overall business
试图定义整体业务
aspect of Jakarta EE we are in the
雅加达EE的方面
process of define
定义过程
the specification process we need to
我们需要的规范过程
protect the jacquard EEE brand okay so
保护提花EEE品牌好吧
it's more of a business aspect as what
这更像是业务方面
the working group is looking at there's
工作组正在研究
a few committees that make up this
组成这个的几个委员会
working group we have a steering
工作组，我们有一个指导
committee and that's you know it's just
委员会，那就是你知道的
basically oversees everything we get
基本上监督我们得到的一切
input from all the other committees and
其他所有委员会的意见，以及
every everybody else that's working on
其他正在努力的人
different sub projects and then you know
不同的子项目，然后您知道
we're able to vote on it deciding what
我们可以对它进行投票以决定什么
to do to go forward we have the
要做前进，我们有
marketing committee
营销委员会
I don't directly participate on that one
我不直接参加那个
so I can't speak to it exactly but you
所以我不能确切地说，但是你
know we get input from them on how are
知道我们从他们那里得到了输入
we going to promote this brand how you
我们将如何推广这个品牌
know this conference is part of this
知道这次会议是其中的一部分
promotion so we do newsletters we do
促销，所以我们做时事通讯
blogs we try to get the word out about
我们试图通过博客来宣传
Jakarta EE and then the specification
Jakarta EE，然后是规格
committee I'm on that committee as well
我也是那个委员会的成员
and that's one that we are trying to
这就是我们正在尝试的
define the process so we have the jsr
定义过程，所以我们有了jsr
process in the JCP and we're moving that
JCP中的流程，我们正在移动
over to Jakarta and we need a
到雅加达，我们需要一个
specification process the draft we
规格说明草案我们
released last week I would highly
上周发布，我会高度评价
encourage everyone to at least take a
鼓励大家至少参加
look at it take a read through it and
看一看就读完了
see if there's anything in there that
看看里面是否有东西
just does not make sense makes you
只是没有道理让你
uncomfortable if you have any nice
如果你有什么好不舒服的
comments you could give those as well
您也可以给这些评论
but we're gonna take comments until the
但我们要发表评论直到
end of the month then we have to kind of
月底，那么我们必须
re-evaluate and find out well how bad
重新评估并找出问题的严重程度
were the comments do we have to redo a
我们必须重做一个评论吗
bunch of stuff or is it just nits and we
一堆东​​西还是只是尼特，我们
can pretty it up and make a final draft
可以把它整理好并作最后草案
we also have one project that's going to
我们也有一个项目要
be our guinea pig and they're going to
成为我们的豚鼠，他们将
help us refine this process so they are
帮助我们完善此过程，以便他们
in the process of creating a
在创建一个
specification project and then they will
规范项目，然后他们将
be working with us trying to follow the
与我们合作，努力遵循
process seen if the process works we
流程，看流程是否可行，我们
will give feedback to them and we hope
会给他们反馈，我们希望
it's a give-and-take
这是一个让步
if we go down one level kind of maybe
如果我们走下一层
you could think of them kind of even but
你甚至可以想到他们
I think of them going down a little bit
我认为他们会下降一点
level because we're getting a little bit
水平，因为我们得到了一点
closer to the code now is with the
现在更接近代码的是
project management committee for the EE
电子工程项目管理委员会
4j project the EE 4j is the top level
4j项目EE 4j是最高级别
project with anyclip so this is where
使用anyclip进行投影，所以这是
all the code lives and code you know it
所有代码都存在，您知道的代码
will eventually include the
最终将包括
specifications and then the API is the
规格，然后API是
tcks any implementations they are part
讨论它们所包含的任何实现
of the EE 4j top-level project you'll
EE 4j顶级项目
notice we have various people from all
注意我们有各种各样的人
the various companies the the what
各种公司是什么
strategic members of jacquard EEE
提花电子电气设备的战略成员
everybody is represented on that
每个人都有代表
everyone has the same vote we do have
每个人都有相同的投票权
Ivar I don't know how many of you know
伊瓦尔我不知道你们中有多少人
Ivar is I know he works for a company
伊瓦尔（Ivar）我知道他在一家公司工作
but he's kind of an independent when
但是当他是一个独立的人
he's working in this role he's our lead
他正在担任这个角色他是我们的领导
for the PMC he does a fantastic job if
对于PMC，如果
you guys know him you know give a shout
你们认识他，你们知道喊
out to him this gives you a view of all
向他展示这一切
of the projects the Eclipse projects
Eclipse项目中的项目
under EE for J if you're familiar with
如果您熟悉，请在EE for J下
Java EE you will see several of them
Java EE您将看到其中的几个
that make sense you know we tried to
有道理，你知道我们试图
match him up with the other Java EE
将他与其他Java EE配对
technologies this is another view of
技术，这是另一种观点
where we are at with our progress you'll
我们在哪里取得进展，您将
notice that almost all of the projects
注意几乎所有的项目
are out to 80% and what that means is
达到80％，这意味着
all of the the project has been
所有的项目都已经
provisioned well the code has been
很好地提供了代码
delivered we can build it we can test it
交付，我们可以构建它，我们可以对其进行测试
and the final item to get it out to a
最后的项目将其发布到
hundred percent is yes you have followed
百分百是的，您一直关注
the Eclipse process and you have done a
Eclipse流程，您已经完成了
release okay now the first projects to
现在发布第一个项目
get to a release they were quite simple
发布它们非常简单
because they were already Eclipse
因为他们已经是Eclipse
projects so we had Eclipse link JSON B
项目，所以我们有了Eclipse链接JSON B
JSON P those got to a hundred percent
JSON P那些达到百分之一百
really quick because they already
非常快，因为他们已经
existed okay
存在没关系
now the one bonus and why Marcus is here
现在一个奖金，为什么马库斯在这里
is because of jax-rs
是因为jax-rs
they were the first
他们是第一个
project that works through this whole
贯穿整个项目的项目
process figured out how to do an eclipse
弄清楚如何做日食的过程
release and then actually you're the
释放，然后实际上你是
first ones to do the new Jakarta maven
第一批做新的雅加达专家
coordinates as well so that's why I
以及坐标，这就是为什么我
wanted to work with Marcus to have him
想和马库斯一起工作
give his view of what you know what
让他对你知道的事情有看法
they're doing at a lower level just want
他们只是想在较低的水平上做
to touch on this before I give it over
在我放弃之前先谈一下
to Marcus we also are doing our CI CD
到Marcus，我们也在制作CI CD
process this has been a huge undertaking
过程这是一项艰巨的任务
and I cannot believe the progress that
我不敢相信进展
we have had in like the last two weeks
就像过去两个星期一样
when I started to pull this chart into
当我开始将此图表拖入
my set of charts about two weeks ago
我大约两周前的一组图表
this column over here for the done that
在此完成此专栏
only had five tasks done that was about
只完成了大约五个任务
two weeks ago and then right before I
两周前，然后在我之前
left I refreshed it it got up to about
离开后我刷新了它
80 projects or 80 tasks being done and
完成80个项目或80个任务，
then last night I refreshed it one last
然后昨天晚上我刷新了它
time and the neat thing here what is it
时间和整洁的东西在这里是什么
133 103 done but the really nice thing
133103做过，但真正的好事
this one's down to zero so even
这个数字降为零，甚至
yesterday during the day we still had to
昨天在白天，我们仍然不得不
turn those off when I'm presenting so we
在我演示时将其关闭，所以我们
have made fantastic progress in the last
最后取得了惊人的进步
couple of weeks our original goal was to
我们最初的目标是
have this all done by this past Monday
在过去的星期一之前完成所有这些工作
but now our goal is this coming Monday
但是现在我们的目标是这个星期一
we have made so much progress I think
我认为我们取得了很大进步
we're getting come really close to
我们真的很接近
having this done and why is this
做完了，这是为什么
important
重要
no I got a focus back on there it's
不，我重新关注了
because we are trying to release eclipse
因为我们正试图释放日食
GlassFish 5.1 so last weekend we did the
GlassFish 5.1，所以上周末我们做了
rc1 for eclipse GlassFish 5.1 that's our
eclipse GlassFish 5.1的rc1是我们的
first golden build of everything in
一切的第一个黄金建造
Eclipse for making GlassFish this was a
用于制作GlassFish的Eclipse
huge milestone for us we were driving so
对我们来说，这是一个巨大的里程碑
hard to have this ready by eclipse con
很难通过eclipse con来准备
and by Oracle code 1 and we just made it
通过Oracle代码1，我们就做到了
it was just over this past weekend
刚刚过去的那个周末
before the conferences started
会议开始之前
we are very happy to make this now we're
我们很高兴现在能做到这一点
not done I'm guessing we're gonna have
还没完成，我想我们会
several RC candidates going through
几个RC候选人通过
before we're finally done with 5.1 but
在我们最终完成5.1之前，但是
the goal of eclipse 5.1 or eclipse
Eclipse 5.1或Eclipse的目标
GlassFish 5.1 is to be Java EE eight
GlassFish 5.1将成为Java EE八
compliant and then we can say that we're
合规，然后我们可以说我们
done with that first deliverable gate so
完成了第一个可交付的门
that's what I wanted to cover from a
这就是我想从
larger community viewpoint and now I'm
更大的社区观点，现在我
gonna turn it over to Marcus and talk
要交给马库斯谈谈
about the team level oh that was a race
关于团队水平哦，那是一场比赛
okay yeah hi I'm Marcus for those who
好的，嗨，我是Marcus，
know me before
以前认识我
okay I'm one of several committees of
好的，我是以下几个委员会之一
checks arrests and I was invited by
检查逮捕，我受邀请
Kevin to share my view on the progress
凯文分享我对进度的看法
so far on the future and so on and it's
到目前为止，等等。
a bit biased because I was in a
有点偏见，因为我在
different organization before which is a
不同的组织之前
chase EP so I'm not a native Eclipse guy
追逐EP，所以我不是本地Eclipse家伙
so what I tell you now is possibly an
所以我现在告诉你的可能是
outside view what we noticed how things
外面看我们注意到了什么
work better or not so good in the
在工作中表现更好还是不太好
Eclipse Foundation where do we come from
Eclipse Foundation来自哪里
everyone you can just just a few words
每个人，您只需要说几句话
where we come from in about 2008 I had
我大约在2008年来自哪里
to program something I I later learned
编程后来学到的东西
it's called rest and I'd not to do
叫做休息，我不愿意做
everything from scratch so I looked
从头开始的一切，所以我看着
around what's there and some friends at
周围有什么，有些朋友在
the Oracle told me they were working
甲骨文告诉我他们正在工作
something in this direction so they
在这个方向上有一些东西，所以他们
invited me to help and to contribute and
邀请我帮助和贡献
what was the nd and was that I developed
那是什么，我发展了什么
a project which is called WebDAV support
一个称为WebDAV支持的项目
for sure say then we had a small argue
可以肯定地说，然后我们有一个小争论
and then it was web dev support for
然后是Web开发人员对
jax-rs
杰克斯
because they wanted me to use native or
因为他们要我使用本机或
stuff and I said I will won't do that I
东西，我说我不会那样做
will stick with all the standard api's
将坚持使用所有标准api
and so we had to invent something
所以我们不得不发明一些东西
because checks RS o dot eight was not
因为检查RS o点8不是
major enough so I invented some ap ice
足够专业，所以我发明了一些冰
on top of that which later became part
最重要的是后来成为一部分
of Czech Terez 101 and so we we we're a
的捷克Terez 101，所以我们我们是
small family working on that not many
小家庭工作不多
people or companies new checks arrests
人员或公司新支票被捕
in the first and it was mostly driven by
在第一，它主要是由
Oracle with some external contributors
Oracle和一些外部贡献者
like me I later was invited to serve at
像我一样，我后来应邀在
Chase or 311 and three three nine and
大通或311和三三九和
374 the later checks arrests versions as
374以后的检查将版本逮捕为
an individual expert and you know it was
一位专家，你知道那是
fun to work with all the companies but
与所有公司合作很有趣，但是
it was always the case that we were only
总是这样，我们只是
hurt but we had no really a voice yeah
受伤，但我们没有声音，是的
so the Oracle I said what do you think
所以甲骨文我说你怎么看
about this what do you think about that
关于这个你怎么看
we did something here this full stop and
我们在这个句号做了一些事情，
whether they did what we wanted or not
他们是否做了我们想要的
was their decision so we could talk we
是他们的决定，所以我们可以谈谈
could see things upfront but we had no
可以预见事物，但是我们没有
vote on this this is different from
对此进行投票，这与
other days ours were explained Elector
其他日子我们被解释为选举人
experts head bowed here it was only
专家团长在这里低头
Oracle and and that was or we a point
甲骨文，那就是我们的观点
where we got angry you talk and talk and
在我们生气的地方你说话又说话，
talk and make arguments and and you
说话和争论，然后你
don't get what you need so we were
没有得到您需要的东西，所以我们
really happy when we saw that Eclipse
当我们看到Eclipse时真的很高兴
Foundation tried to check the rest in a
基金会试图检查其余的
really open fashion and I don't know
真正开放的时尚，我不知道
somehow I was invited to join and
不知何故我被邀请加入
yeah this is the past and I well
是的，这是过去，我很好
somewhat somebody will start that thing
有些人会开始那件事
so I waited for it restart well nothing
所以我等待它重启
happened so what to do then it was
发生了，所以该怎么办
January and I had this lot of ideas and
一月和我有很多想法
I wanted to do something but there was
我想做点什么，但是有
nothing so I I thought I should do
没什么，所以我以为我应该做
something so I kicked off a discussion
事情，所以我开始了讨论
so a sort of introduction hello is
所以介绍一下你好
everybody here can somebody hear me in
这里的每个人都可以听到我的声音
the forum and yeah there there were a
论坛，是的，那里有一个
few answers and so we simply started to
几个答案，所以我们只是开始
work we had no idea of the eclipse
工作，我们不知道日食
processes we had no idea of our own
我们不知道自己的过程
status we just saw there is code let's
我们刚刚看到的状态是有代码让我们
do something so we did and and these are
做一些我们做到的事情，这些是
really bad because shortly after we
真的很糟糕，因为不久之后
learned this some Constitution like the
学会了像这样的一些宪法
Eclipse development process and we
Eclipse开发过程和我们
should follow it okay so we try to
应该遵循它，所以我们尝试
follow it and then we learned there are
跟随它，然后我们了解到
different roles
不同的角色
we are committed oh yeah I noticed this
我们承诺哦，是的，我注意到了这一点
is a funny story I noticed I can clear
我发现我可以清除一个有趣的故事
to master branch I actually had that
掌握分支我实际上有
access right granted but it was not a
授予访问权，但不是
good that you do it I I did it in in the
很好，我做到了
best way I could I tried I solve some
我尝试解决问题的最好方法
problems so it's it's really good code
问题，这是非常好的代码
base but alright well it's a bad idea
基地，但好吧，这是一个坏主意
because they can throw any into it
因为他们可以把任何东西扔进去
and see that later
等一下再见
so first dispute with this Oracle and in
所以首先与这个甲骨文和
in this experiment we're a year to to
在这个实验中，我们一年来
work in this project we discovered all
在这个项目中工作，我们发现了所有
the rules of the Eclipse Foundation we
Eclipse Foundation的规则
discovered our powers that we have as
发现了我们拥有的力量
committees which are really huge and we
真正庞大的委员会，我们
discovered that there are others and in
发现那里还有其他人
Germany the Constitution says your own
德国宪法说你自己
powers end where the powers of others
权力终结于他人的权力
are interfered so what does that mean
被干扰了，那是什么意思
well I I can clear to master branch okay
好II可以清除到主分支好了
I can do that I have this power well
我可以做到，我拥有这种力量
that's maybe not a good idea so you
那可能不是一个好主意，所以你
shouldn't do it okay
不应该这样做
on the other hand the other persons or
另一方面，其他人或
the other rows also ruin things for
其他行也毁了
example that a project lead is not to
例如，项目负责人不愿意
the king he cannot do what he wants
国王，他无法做自己想做的事
the committers are king you didn't know
提交者是你不知道的国王
that he learned from me I told him and
他从我那里学到了，我告诉他，
there are others like the PMC the PMC
还有其他像PMC PMC
members what are PMC members I didn't
成员我没有的PMC成员
know that so I tried out to do things
知道，所以我尝试做事
and I asked him he said ok and one PMC
我问他，他说还可以，还有一个PMC
member said yes yes that no the third
成员说是是不是第三
said what I'm a PMC member the whole the
说我整个都是PMC成员
whole year 2018 was it was some kind of
整个2018年是某种
hot right in this project because we
这个项目很热门，因为我们
wanted to deliver one still deliver fast
想交付一个仍然快速交付
we wanted to do all the routes the
我们想做所有的路线
Eclipse Foundation said we wanted to do
Eclipse Foundation说我们想做
it right but everybody wants to do it
没错，但每个人都想做
another way so this is that the most
换句话说，这是最
hard thing we had to learn how to build
我们必须学习如何构建困难的事情
a team how to work in the same way this
一个团队如何以这种相同的方式工作
is what the Eclipse rules do not tell
是Eclipse规则所不具备的
you so you need a leader if you don't
你，所以你需要一个领导者，如果你不
have a leader everybody waits so Kevin
有一个领导者大家都在等，所以凯文
says I'm too development lead ok i i'm
说我也太领先了，我是
i'm the one who triggers the discussions
我是引发讨论的人
if you don't do that discussions will
如果您不这样做，讨论将
just go away they stop somehow because
只是走开，他们以某种方式停下来，因为
people don't tend to regularly look up
人们不会经常去抬头
all the open issues so somebody has to
所有未解决的问题，所以有人必须
do it
做吧
i'm the one who starts voting called for
我是开始投票的人
refuse and all that so if you call that
拒绝等等，如果您打电话给那
elite ok the anomaly the other thing
精英好吧，反常
what we did is write code so i talked a
我们所做的是编写代码，所以我说了一个
lot of the things that happened in an
很多事情发生在
organizational way but there also
组织方式，但也有
happened a lot to to code if you look at
如果您看，发生了很多编码工作
the master branch they actually I don't
他们实际上我不知道的主分支
know 50 or 80 I I don't know
知道50或80 II不知道
contributions already so we were not
已经有捐款了，所以我们没有
just first but did release
刚开始但是发布了
we also added useful things like bug
我们还添加了一些有用的东西，例如错误
fixes clarifications for a specification
修正规范说明
and so on and so on and we actually
等等等等，我们实际上
won't say that we have a release we just
不会说我们有一个发布，我们只是
followed the rules and the Eclipse
遵循规则和Eclipse
Foundation says this is a release
基金会说这是发布
technical this is a real spot for us it
技术对我们来说这是一个真实的地方
is just a correction the actual work
仅是实际工作的更正
having a different branch and that
有一个不同的分支
different branch contains new api's so
不同的分支包含新的api
there is really things come in and check
真的有东西进来检查
the rest which will be in Jakarta ee9
其余的将在雅加达ee9中
mostly I think which are very beneficial
我主要认为这是非常有益的
for the future like for the cloud like
像云一样的未来
for a PMS foot but the futures from Java
PMS脚，但Java的未来
online and so on and so on
在线等等
so at the point right now what we try to
所以就目前而言，我们试图
do also with this presentation it get
通过此演示文稿也可以做到
more people into - both on the code side
更多的人投入了-在代码方面
we have a lot of committers which is an
我们有很多提交者，
organizational role actually we have too
实际上我们也有组织角色
many computers we need to get rid of
我们需要摆脱的许多计算机
some well if I say please everybody
好吧，如果我说请大家
would I only count be your forwards but
我只算你的前锋，
we have 3000 mtres so with actually
我们有3000米，实际上
there are people I don't know if they
有些人我不知道他们是否
read the messages at all
完全阅读消息
so we have to clean up things but then
所以我们必须清理东西
we need real contributions from the
我们需要来自
outside from you from external ones who
从你外面到外面的人
have good ideas who need features who
有好主意谁需要功能谁
find bugs who want to clarify things in
查找想要澄清问题的错误
a specification and so on and also we we
规范等等，我们也
need real committers people who are
需要真正的提交者
willing to review external contributions
愿意审查外部捐款
to work with the contributors to give
与贡献者一起努力
advise how to write the code how to
建议如何编写代码
invent and good api which is not very
发明和良好的API不是很
easy I learned that with my own API so I
很容易，我通过自己的API得知了这一点，所以我
had a good idea this was in made the
有个好主意，
work was done in October so it's a long
工作在十月份完成，所以很长
way to get in a good API and we want to
获得良好API的方法，我们希望
invite invite everybody to participate
邀请邀请大家参加
in our project so we can have a real
在我们的项目中，这样我们可以有一个真正的
release with real new feature
发布具有真正的新功能
with a really free and open team which
一个真正自由开放的团队
includes our ally I don't want to kick
包括我不想踢的盟友
out or record to clearly say it I invite
出去或记录清楚地说出我邀请
everybody but we need to learn that
每个人，但我们需要学习
external contributions are worth
外部贡献值得
discussion not like back in JCP times
讨论不像JCP时代
when I said oh it's nice that you did
当我说哦，很高兴你做到了
something but we don't even discuss it
些什么，但我们什至不讨论
so this is what Oracle learned in this
这就是Oracle从中学到的
year that external contributors are
外部贡献者的年份
worse to talk with and we learned how to
更糟糕的交谈，我们学会了
work with those people at Oracle that
与Oracle的那些人一起工作
have understood that so right now we are
已经了解了，所以现在我们是
an open source project we have an open
一个开源项目，我们有一个开放的
source product it's an active project
源产品，这是一个活跃的项目
and you all are invited to help to form
大家都被邀请帮助形成
the future which we have here on the
我们在这里的未来
slide our next target is waiting for
滑动我们的下一个目标正在等待
class fish because it's hard to do a
上鱼，因为很难做
release on a major adopter of the
发布主要采用者
project and to progress at the same time
项目并同时进行
so actually we just wait a few weeks
所以实际上我们只等几个星期
before we go on and then the big plan is
在我们继续之前，大计划是
open so join our team you're invited
打开，加入我们的团队，您受邀
tell us your IDs in issue tracker tell
告诉我们您的问题跟踪器ID
us box
我们盒子
tell us what features you want tell us
告诉我们您想要什么功能
the changes you want tell up the big
您想要的变化说明了一切
targets you you you go for whether is
定位您要去的目标
shape him as whether it's micro service
塑造他是否是微服务
whether it's inclusion of micro profile
是否包含微观特征
or or whatever tell us discuss with us
或任何告诉我们与我们讨论的东西
and don't be shy you will be heard you
别害羞，你会被听到的
were worth to be discussed with as his
值得与他讨论
Oracle as his IBM and well yes that's
甲骨文是他的IBM，是的，
mostly it and if you have questions for
主要是它，如果您有疑问
me or programming then just go on and
我或编程然后继续
ask oh let me add just a couple of
问哦，让我加几个
things I don't need that yeah um so I
我不需要那个东西，所以我
know he's been giving the jax-rs angle
知道他一直在给jax-rs角
you know the idea I showed 39 projects
你知道我展示了39个项目的想法
oh I'm should I move okay
哦，我应该走了吗
yeah you know we have 39 projects out
是的，您知道我们有39个项目
there so if Jax our else isn't you know
在那里，如果杰克斯，我们不知道
your favorite flavor I mean we've got a
你最喜欢的味道，我是说我们有一个
lot of other projects to get involved
许多其他项目参与其中
with and it could be the API is it could
与它可能是API是否可以
be the tcks it could be documentation
可能是文档
there's all kinds of ways to get
有各种各样的方法
involved the other thing I wanted to
涉及我想做的另一件事
point out and I think Marcus is a very
指出，我认为马库斯是一个非常
good example of how the community is
社区是一个很好的例子
supposed to work together because I
应该一起工作，因为我
don't even know the project lead for
甚至都不知道项目负责人
jax-rs
杰克斯
what what is really yeah what's his name
什么是真的，他叫什么名字
he's Santiago okay Santiago I've never
他是圣地亚哥，好吧，圣地亚哥，我从来没有
met him okay he is the project lead but
认识他好吧，他是项目负责人，但是
that doesn't mean you know it's not like
那并不意味着你知道那不是
an expert group lead he doesn't have
他没有的专家组负责人
final say on everything it's the group
最终决定权归小组所有
it's the community that's going to
这将是社区
decide Santiago has been a little bit
决定圣地亚哥已经有点
more quiet I don't know why but maybe
更安静，我不知道为什么，但也许
he's busy with other things you know
他正忙着其他事情
whatever
随你
so Marcus took the lead he's a committer
所以马库斯（Marcus）率领他是一名提交人
it really doesn't matter he saw a hole
他看见一个洞真的没关系
he wanted to start filling in some of
他想开始填写一些
the things he started the discussion
他开始讨论的事情
started doing some commits somewhere a
开始在某处做一些提交
little too early we had to back them out
太早了，我们不得不退后
a little bit but you know it's that type
有点，但你知道那是那种类型
of initiative that actually makes it
真正做到的主动性
much more fun you know instead of just
您知道的不仅有趣，而且不仅仅是
waiting around for someone else to start
等待别人开始
doing the work as committers you can all
可以作为提交者来完成工作
start doing the work so that was a very
开始做这项工作，这是一个非常
good point that Marcus made earlier I
马库斯早些时候提出的好观点
just want to emphasize that okay
只想强调一点
anything else yeah I want to amend that
是的，我想修改一下
if you're looking at check out REE at
如果您正在查看REE，请访问
the hole we have a bad situation in some
我们在某些情况下遇到的困境
projects there are some projects that
项目中有一些项目
they don't have a lead there are
他们没有领先优势
committees but nobody wants to be delete
委员会，但没人希望被删除
but it it's hard for the control if you
但是如果你很难控制
have I don't know 50 or 80 projects I
我不知道我有50个项目还是80个项目
didn't count it and and you you cannot
没有算，你就不能
have one person to talk to but you have
有一个人可以交谈，但是你有
ten or twenty to address
十或二十
it's really really hard to get answers
真的很难得到答案
soon to get concise art answers to get
即将获得简洁的艺术答案
authoritative answers so we we even are
权威的答案，所以我们甚至
seeking project leads at the moment and
目前正在寻找项目负责人，
it's easy to become one that if nobody
如果没有人，很容易成为一个
else wants I do it so nowadays casts it
别人想要我这样做，所以今天投下
currently funny site at the Eclipse
Eclipse中当前有趣的网站
Foundation really is about people it's
基金会真的是关于人的
not about companies
与公司无关
it's about people so don't wait for your
这是关于人的，所以不要等你的
employer to become a member just stand
用人单位成为会员
out and say I do it I as a person will
出来说我做我作为一个人会
will help as a contributor as the
会像
committee as a project lead I will serve
委员会作为项目负责人，我将担任
in the PMC like I word us for example
在PMC中，例如我说的话
assume then in spare time actually
假设然后在业余时间
yeah well and if you have technical
是的，如果您有技术
questions you can talk to me or any any
您可以与我或任何其他人交谈的问题
other contributor there is no no address
其他贡献者没有地址
where you have to wait for a ticket to
你必须在那等票
get answered you can just talk to real
得到答案，你可以说实话
people and that's the right thing at a
人，这是正确的事情
Cleese foundation there are other bad
克莱氏基金会还有其他坏处
things we have a lot of discussion like
我们有很多讨论的事情
in every democracy okay we module names
在每个民主国家，好吧，我们对名称进行模块化
for is insulin yeah like a knock your
因为胰岛素像敲门一样
name is your example or another bad
名字是你的榜样或另一个不好的例子
thing
事情
I just come late we don't have a general
我来晚了，我们没有将军
roadmap we have a shared idea we want to
路线图，我们有一个共同的想法，我们想
make progress towards Jakarta 8 &amp; 9
在雅加达8和9取得进展
but how normal people like me have a
但是像我这样的普通人如何
different vision then I don't know the
不同的视野，然后我不知道
payara team for example in the whole or
例如，整体而言，payara团队或
like completely like IBM they won't have
就像完全没有IBM一样
different visions how to get there so
不同的愿景如何到达那里
everybody has an idea and some have
每个人都有一个主意，有些人有
their ideas early and some have them
他们的想法很早，有的有
late and it was a very very rare late
晚了，这是非常非常罕见的晚
idea to change to module thanks actually
更改为模块的想法实际上谢谢
we had two releases of jax-rs
我们有两个版本的jax-rs
out there in search mavin dog standing
搜寻mavin狗站立
there listed and then I got a notice
在那里列出，然后我收到通知
from I think David province that he
我认为戴维省他
thinks it's a very really
认为这是非常非常
I need to change to check EMS module
我需要更改以检查EMS模块
names actually I'm no J PMS extra I
其实我不是J PMS
don't know if that breaks
不知道这有没有坏
backwards-compatibility but everything
向后兼容，但一切
that would so what to do now
那现在该怎么办
we have to decide about that up there's
我们必须决定那件事
an ongoing discussion so but but it's in
正在进行的讨论中，但是它在
the open it's very transparent
打开它是非常透明的
I mean sometimes there's you know
我的意思是有时候你知道
back-channel discussions I mean
我的意思是反向渠道讨论
sometimes you just have to do that but
有时您只需要这样做，但是
then you bring that forward and you get
然后你提出来，你得到
it out in front of everybody
摆在大家面前
right so right yeah it's a great thing
对，对，对，这很棒
to be part of that and if you don't have
成为其中的一部分，如果您没有
more questions I think what we obsession
我想我们还有更多疑问
yeah any questions yeah right mole yes
是的，任何问题，是的，正确的痣，是的
okay so um his question was with the new
好的，所以他的问题是关于新
specification process it kind of
规范过程
requires individual specification
需要个别规格
projects and how many of those do we
项目以及我们有多少项目
already have in place with that full
已经有足够的空间
list of projects that we have identified
我们确定的项目清单
so far kind of your question okay
到目前为止，您的问题还好
I mean out let me just kind of speak to
我的意思是让我只是和我说话
it and then we'll see if we covered it
它，然后我们看看是否覆盖了它
or not
或不
so most maybe 75% of the projects were
因此，大概有75％的项目是
already separated so the specification
已经分开，所以规格
projects are the ones that we say like
项目就是我们所说的
the project for jax-rs the project for
jax-rs的项目
JMS or a JMS api those are going to be
JMS或JMS api将会是
specification projects so the
规范项目，所以
specification projects will include the
规范项目将包括
specifications the API is
API的规格
we believe the tcks are going to go in
我们相信这些小问题将会继续
there as well there's still a little
那里还有一点
question mark there but that that's the
问号在那里，但这就是
extent of the specification projects any
规范项目的范围
implementations are going to be separate
实现将是分开的
now that's where there's a few projects
现在那里有几个项目
that the way they came from Oracle they
他们来自甲骨文的方式
were all combined and well actually I
都结合在一起，实际上我
think we had two separate Jersey because
认为我们有两个单独的球衣，因为
Jersey had the API he mixed in with the
泽西岛将他与
implementation we had to separate those
实施我们必须将那些分开
two so we had the jax-rs API project in
两个，所以我们有一个jax-rs API项目
Jersey um and I know there's a couple
泽西岛，我知道有几个
other projects that we still have to do
我们仍然要做的其他项目
that separation and we will we just we
这种分离，我们将我们只是我们
don't were just trying to make progress
不只是在努力取得进展
with creating the GlassFish so there's
创建GlassFish，所以有
one thing to to amend actually for us it
实际上为我们修改的一件事
was an easy thing when Jersey and checks
当球衣和支票是一件容易的事
RS was mixed up because you can do a
RS混为一谈，因为您可以
work in one stream it just have one
在一个流中工作只有一个
commit for the whole idea but on the
致力于整个想法，但是
other hand it's it would still repeat
另一方面，它仍然会重复
what Oracle did and we didn't want to do
甲骨文做了什么，我们不想做
that because Jersey has no special role
因为泽西岛没有特殊作用
anymore Jersey is not the implementation
不再是泽西岛不是执行
the embryo of check the rest it's just
检查剩下的只是它的胚芽
one implementation anymore so even if
一种实现，即使
Jersey would would die I I don't hope so
泽西岛会死II不希望如此
I'm a Jersey commuter also it it will
我也是新泽西州的通勤者
not affect tracks or ass and that's a
不影响轨道或屁股，这是一个
good thing because the checks are as
好东西，因为检查是
team wants checks or ass as an API to
团队希望将检查或屁股作为API
survive so possibly you come up with
生存，所以你可能想出
your home prune implementation and you
您的家庭修剪实施，您
can go to the specification team and let
可以去规格团队，让
it certify that you did it correctly and
它证明您做得正确，并且
this is a good thing it did was horribly
这是一件令人震惊的好事
in the past it was completely an Oracle
在过去，它完全是一个Oracle
show so you had to go to Oracle and ask
表演，所以你不得不去甲骨文问
them if how much you have to pay to get
他们，如果你必须付出多少才能得到
certification and now it's a clear
认证，现在很清楚
process it's documented how it works
记录它如何工作
everybody can let his product be
每个人都可以让他的产品成为
certified as complying to the
证明符合
specification and that's why it's good
规范，这就是为什么它很好
thing that we have this separation of
我们有这种分离的东西
projects and even if it's more hard to
项目，即使很难
add new features now did that answer
现在添加新功能就可以了
your question
你的问题
okay okay five minutes left so we have
好的，还剩五分钟，所以我们有
plenty of time for questions any other
有足够的时间问其他问题
questions okay so we can sign you all up
问题还可以，所以我们可以注册大家
on the jacket arresting I have my laptop
在夹克外套上，我有我的笔记本电脑
here so I can make you commit oh right
在这里，我可以让你犯错
now yeah okay that's it thank you very
现在是的，很好，非常感谢
much thank you
非常感谢你